♪ It seems today
that all you see ♪
♪ Is violence in movies
and sex on TV ♪
♪ But where are those
good old-fashioned values ♪
♪ On which we used to rely? ♪
♪ Lucky there's a family guy ♪
♪ Lucky there's a man
who positively can do ♪
♪ All the things that make us ♪
♪ Laugh and cry ♪
♪ He's... a...
Fam... ily... Guy! ♪
Ugh, look at Miss Tammy.
What a skank.
She's free-muffin it
at a baby school.
Hi, Stewie.
Mommy's here to pick you up.
Why do you feel
the need to narrate
every little thing you do?
Oh, hi, Mrs. Griffin.
You know, I've
actually been meaning
to talk to you
about Stewie.
I'm concerned that he might
have an attention problem.
Attention problem?
Yes, he's been a little
difficult to deal with,
and on page two of three in the
How To Be a Teacher manual,
it says that any child
who's being difficult
should be medicated.
What?! Drugging a baby?
Are you sure?
That sounds so serious.
I'm afraid his behavior has
been an issue for a while.
He's even been bothering
students during nap time.
Hey, you up?
Guess where
I have a crayon.
So, I spend, like,
$75 on cat toys,
and what does she play with?
A shoelace.
That's crazy.
Joe, that's been your answer
every time I tell a story.
It's like
you're not even listening.
Well, that's 'cause
you interrupted me
when I was telling
you about Kevin
trying to hang himself
with an extension cord.
I know, that's crazy.
Hey, y'all want to try
some of our new food?
I'm trying to turn this place
into a gastropub.
These are Korean tacos, 'cause
whatever the hell nowadays.
Ugh! These are terrible!
(laughs)
Quagmire,
when it comes to tacos,
I'll trust the Koreans,
thank you.
You're nuts. This tastes like
Ani DiFranco after a bike ride.
Geez, Quagmire, since when are
you such an expert on food?
For your information,
I'm an excellent cook.
(laughs):
You? A cook?
Huh. What's your specialty?
No-way soufflé?
(laughs) I'm sorry,
that was out of line.
I am a good cook,
and I'll prove it to you!
Saturday night, you
and all your wives are coming
to my place for dinner.
Fine. We'll be there.
Ooh, can we make it
Sunday?
Saturday, I'm giving
Javier Bardem a haircut.
So, what'll it be?
Everything.
What do you mean?
Long in the short places,
short in the long places.
It should be from both
the future and the past.
Something a child
would do to a doll.
Sorry, I just prefer
to do number two at home.
Where were we?
It's Stewie,
Dr. Hartman.
He's having trouble
focusing at school.
Ah, yes. So you're telling me
your baby won't sit still
in a way that's convenient
for his teacher?
Yes.
I'd heard stories,
but never thought
I'd see it
with my own eyes.
Mrs. Griffin, I'm going
to write Stewie a prescription
for ADHD medication.
Really? Well,
I don't know.
Doesn't that stuff
make you wired?
Well, if you're low-energy
and lethargic, yes.
But if you're high energy,
it actually calms you down
and helps you focus.
At least that's what I'm reading
on WebMD.
Wow, there are a lot
of different kinds of medicines.
There's a cat in here.
Okay, I guess we
can give it a try.
Here you go.
Now, who's this little guy?
Wow, when did you learn
to cook, Glenn?
Well, as a young man, I found
that a great meal was the
quickest way to a woman's heart.
How romantic.
I mean, how do you think NBA
players get all those chicks?
They're all great cooks.
Except Kobe Bryant.
His-his... his secret
is different.
Quagmire, you're really good.
You could probably
make money at this.
Yeah, maybe you could
open a restaurant.
Or maybe get a cooking show.
You know,
the 11:30 cooking show
on Channel Five
needs a new host.
The old one burned off
his eyebrows,
and was just too weird
to look at.
You should do
it, Quagmire!
I'll even come along
and cheer you on!
You'd do that for me?
Course I would.
I love cheering people on,
like when I go to NASCAR.
(crowd cheering)
Go in a circle!
Advertise stuff!
Advertise Stu...!
Go in a circle!
Hey, where's Stewie?
Oh, he's probably
sleeping off his pills.
What?
Well, the school said
he had an attention problem,
so Dr. Hartman gave him
a prescription.
You're giving a
one-year-old drugs?!
You're doping up a baby!
Peter, are you
okay with this?
Will you stop talking?
I'm trying to think about a girl
I saw at the gas station.
(door creaks)
Stewie?
(slowly):
Welcome to Pillow-World, Bri.
Let me get up and greet you.
There we go.
How you doing?
Oh, my God, Stewie,
you're totally drugged out!
You know something?
I have been thinking
about how everyone in this
family, Brian, does their job.
And they do a pretty
good job of it.
God, I'm really freaking
out over this audition.
What if I blow it?
Quagmire, when I agreed
to come to this,
I didn't know it would require
this level of emotional support.
You Glenn Quagmire?
I'm Carson, the
producer of the show.
Peter Griffin.
I should be at work.
Okay, let's see
what you've got.
I think you're gonna like this.
Cedar plank salmon
with a maple glaze
and slow-roasted cherry tomatoes
on a bed of mesclun greens.
Hmm. Not bad.
Also, the tomatoes can be eyes,
and the lettuce can be hair.
Look down.
There's also a carrot.
(laughs) This is great!
Terrific food
and a hilarious sidekick?
This! This
is the show!
What do you mean?
I'm saying
you're hired!
Just as long as your
friend joins you.
What do you say, Peter?
I say let's do it!
Whoops. Uh, uh.
Oh, I'm...
I'm sorry.
What do I...
what-what do I do?
I-I don't...
I don't know what to do now.
That was the wrong choice,
Peter.
Wow, Quagmire,
look at you!
You're a real TV chef!
I know.
It might sound silly,
but being a chef is something
I've always dreamed about.
I always dream about my
house filling up with water.
That's crazy. But anyway, thanks
for encouraging me, Peter.
DIRECTOR:
All right, places!
We're rolling
in three, two, one.
Welcome back to
Quagmire's Kitchen.
Now, this mince pie
is about ready to go.
Just needs a pinch
of cinnamon.
And while we're at it, how about
we take the cinnamon challenge?
Okay, Peter, we've all seen
the Internet videos.
We're not doing that.
I was talking about
something else.
I was talking about a
serious cooking thing.
Now, the ingredients
of a mince pie are traceable
to the 13th century,
when returning European
crusaders brought back
Middle Eastern recipes
containing meats,
fruits and--
oh, boy-- spices.
Right here,
I'm using cloves.
(coughing)
Of course, most people associate
mince pie with Christmas.
(hacking)
But I'll be honest.
I'm not afraid of
a summer mince pie.
I remember the first time
I had mince pie.
Our neighbor, Mrs. Morrin,
introduced it to me one afternoon.
Oh, God!
I had house-sat for her
Aah!
while she was visiting her aunt in Vernon
Oh, God.
and she wanted to thank me.
And, oh, boy,
what a treat it was.
You done?
Yeah.
All right, best two
out of three, cinnamon.
Still on those meds, huh?
Uh, yeah, they, uh...
they help me to, um...
uh... think.
Okay, time for
an eyes-open nap.
God, look what those pills
are doing to you.
Putting you on that stuff
was a huge mistake.
Like inviting a turtle
to a cocktail party.
Hey. Ask me why they
call me a box turtle.
(loud munching)
See, this is how
American society treats unique,
enthusiastic children.
Instead of embracing
their mental gifts,
their first reaction
is to shoot them up
with hard-core drugs
until they're mindless sheeple.
All the better
to send off to Kuwait
and feed the Halliburton
oil machine, right?!
(scoffs):
Bush.
Yup. Takes all kinds.
You know, a lot of kids
at my school take ADD pills.
They say if you're lazy
and unmotivated,
it makes you super energized
and productive.
Rea... Really? Productive?
Yeah. And college kids
take it all the time
so they can focus
on their studies
and drinking alcohol
with their butts.
Focus, huh?
Okay, well, Stewie,
these babies can help
the garbage disposal focus
because that's where
they're going.
No need to follow me,
because I just said
what I was gonna do.
My God, I can't stop!
The words are
just pouring out of me!
I have more energy than a guy
who caught a T-shirt!
(crowd cheering)
My wife can wear this to sleep!
My wife can wear this
to sleep!
Okay, today we're putting
together duck breast medallions
with a port wine reduction.
And as I'm walking you
through the steps,
watch your screen for
Junior Chef Peter's pop-up tips:
helpful hints and food factoids
to make your meal a success.
Now, you're gonna want to start
with a large,
self-sealing plastic bag.
And in that bag,
we'll combine one large,
finely-chopped garlic clove;
one tablespoon of grated,
peeled fresh ginger;
two teaspoons
of five-spice powder;
a teaspoon of salt; and a half
teaspoon of fresh ground pepper.
Then you're gonna want
to add the duck breasts,
seal the bag, and refrigerate
that for at least one hour,
or up to 24 hours, if you want
to prepare this ahead of time.
Just make sure you remove
the bag from the refrigerator
one hour before cooking.
You're gonna put that in your
oven, preheated to 400 degrees.
So we just spoon
on the drippings,
and that'll brown
the skin nicely.
If you bang these metal spoons
on everything, it's like Stomp.
Look at me! I'm huge in 2002!
Peter...
Nothing like a night at the
theater that ends in a headache!
Damn it, Peter,
that's it!
I can't do this show with
you anymore! You're fired!
What?! You can't fire me!
Only Mr. Spacely can fire me.
Griffin...
you're fired!
(voice breaking):
Okay, that's fair.
(crying)
Peter, can
I come in?
Hold on, let me put on
my weird old actress turban.
Yes?
Listen, I saw what happened,
but you should know,
we at the station
would hate to lose you.
You're a big hit
with the viewers.
I will not work
with that man again.
I'm not asking
you to. In fact,
we'd like to offer you
your own cooking show.
Hmm, let me consult
with my lawyer.
Well, Peter, since the DUIs
happened so close together,
we don't really have
much wiggle room here.
I suggest you take the jail time
and just get it over with.
I'll do it.
After October 13.
Come on, Rupert.
Wait-wait till you see this.
This is really
something special.
Check out how much water
is in the dehumidifier.
Wow!
That was all in the air.
(light clattering)
Brian?
Is that... is that, uh...
Is that, uh... you?
Stewie! Rearrange.
Ewiets. Rearrange.
Wieest. Restore.
Stewie. Hey, come see
what I've been working on.
I call it
Space Shire Seven.
Nice, nice.
It's like, uh, it's like
a fake, uh, place you made?
It's a medieval sci-fi universe,
adaptable to TV,
movies, toys, games,
and mobile apps!
I threw together a 2,000-page
treatment last night.
And I just figured,
the hell with it,
why not build a scale model
and record voices
for all the characters? Watch.
Well met, stranger.
Arasha deekaba plitcho.
That's a Nebulon Mage.
He speaks Ga'bi,
this dumb language I wrote.
It's then... illegal?
What?
Hello?
Okay, now we add
the diced tomatoes.
(thumping dance music,
applause in distance)
Just gonna keep going here.
I like to drizzle these
with a fig balsamic...
(crowd cheers in distance)
Damn it.
What the hell
is going on over there?!
♪ I don't want ♪
♪ A place to stay... ♪
And that's my famous paella
that looks and tastes
just like a pizza bagel.
It's a pizza bagel.
Now, as always,
add butter to taste.
Mmm, delicious!
Butter dunk!
(buzzer sounds)
(crowd cheering)
Stop it!
Stop the show!
What the hell
are you doing?
You're just pouring
melted butter onto frozen foods.
You're not a chef.
Oh, really? Then why do I
already have a restaurant
in Orlando's largest
indoor water park?
This is an insult to anyone
who cares about cooking.
Either you leave
the network or I do!
Guys, guys, look, I know how
we can settle this: a cook-off.
Each of you
cooks a meal
using a secret ingredient,
Iron Chef style.
Will we be allowed
to use calculators?
Um, I... I don't...
What?
I say bring it on!
Fine! A cook-off it is.
See you in the
kitchen, jerk.
I'll see you
in hell, loser.
Bad day to carpool.
Yeah.
Okay, Joe, Peter and I
are going head-to-head
in that cooking
competition,
and they're letting us
each use an assistant.
Will you help me out?
Okay, but just promise me
there's no reading.
I'm not a strong reader.
What?
I'm not illiterate,
I'm just slow.
What are you talking about?
I never tried hard in school
'cause I could always run fast.
So you're cool with being
my chef helper for the big show?
Sure, but I got
to be honest--
if it ain't a
fish with whiskers,
I don't know what
to do with it.
But if it is?
Then sweet sassy molassey!
(chuckles)
Great. Don't talk that way
when we're on the show.
♪ ♪
♪ You're taking a chance ♪
♪ Risking it all ♪
♪ For the thrill of the moment ♪
♪ Taking a stand ♪
♪ You ain't gonna fall ♪
♪ And you've always known it ♪
♪ They're dying to shake you ♪
♪ Trying their best
to break you ♪
♪ And though
the going is rough ♪
♪ You're going home as a hero ♪
♪ 'Cause there's
thunder in your heart ♪
♪ Every move is like lightning ♪
♪ It's the power you feel ♪
♪ When you get your taste ♪
♪ Of the glory ♪
♪ You can light the dark ♪
♪ When they hear
your heart of thunder. ♪
Stewie! Stew-ez Canal.
You're here!
We got to get going.
Going?
Where?
To Hartford, man.
There's a book fair
at the convention center,
and George R. R. Martin
will be there.
Who-Who's that?
Uh, Game of Thrones?
Black shirts? Dandruff?
Takes down more nerd chotch
than anyone around?
Okay.
Anyway, I'm gonna
show him my models
and pitch him
Space Shire Seven.
Okay, before we go,
I should wet my eyes.
(slow scraping)
There.
♪ ♪
Good afternoon, I'm Tom Tucker,
and we have a fantastic
cooking competition for you
today with two fantastic chefs.
Really?
You couldn't find another
adjective for "fantastic"?
Used "fantastic" twice?
Who wrote this?
DIRECTOR:
Erica did.
Wait, is that the one
I called fat and we can't fire?
Yeah.
Let's get this
contest started!
Big whoop. I can do that.
(woman screams)
DIRECTOR:
Oh, my God, Erica!
You killed Erica!
TOM:
Fantastic.
That's him.
George R. R. Martin.
God, he must be
the coolest fat guy
in a train conductor's cap
in the world!
Mr. Martin,
I'm Brian Griffin,
and I've got a pitch
that's gonna blow you away.
Are you sitting down?
Almost always.
Then join me
on an interstellar crusade
to Space Shire Seven!
Our story begins
50,000 fortnights ago,
in the distant galaxy
of Warlock's Keep.
Comet Castle falls.
Samson Cyberblood is the new
king of the star system.
Long live
Space Shire Seven,
and long live
the Hyperspeed Throne!
(panting)
So? What do you think?
It was terrible.
Ah, you're
speaking the language
of the Opposite Goblins.
I'm very flattered.
No, it's garbage.
You just took a lot of pills,
mashed together a bunch
of sci-fi and fantasy clichés
and crapped out
a 2,000-page turd.
Y-You could tell
I was on medication?
Oh, sure. But that stuff
doesn't make you write well,
it just makes you
write a lot.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have to go wash the nerd
chotch out of my beard.
God. I didn't realize
how those drugs were
ruining me creatively.
I haven't been feeling
quite right either.
Yesterday, I watched Chris
shower for half an hour
just because
I thought it was the TV.
He, um...
he lies on his back
in there.
Stewie, this drug
is ruining us.
We don't need these.
You're right.
These pills are for people
with real problems.
But there's
nothing wrong with us.
You're just lazy,
I'm just excitable;
we're-we're both normal.
Now let's go home.
(grunting)
That man is an imposter!
I am George R. R. Martin!
Whoa!
♪ ♪
Let's begin
the Channel Five Cook-Off.
Remember, the winner
gets to keep his TV show.
And the secret ingredient is...
butter.
Aw, sweet!
No. That's
Peter's specialty.
I was hoping
the secret ingredient
would be popcorn shrimps.
I liked smacking
your butt earlier.
Are the balls
different from the cubes?
God, what do I do?
Joe, check if we have shallots!
Okay. I can't see
anything on the counter,
but I'll do my best.
Aah! Monster brains!
TOM: Looks like Chef Griffin
is preparing
a delicious five-course
butter feast.
Son of a bitch,
I never cook with butter.
Joe, grab my recipe book
and find a dish
where I can substitute
olive oil with butter.
Joe, come on, hurry!
I told you
I'm not a strong reader!
Damn it, Joe,
pull it together!
Hey, Quagmire, FYI, I got to
take off in, like, ten minutes.
I got a clarinet lesson.
What?! Ugh.
I can't do this.
(sobbing)
Aw, look at Quagmire.
This was his dream.
Time's almost up, Peter.
We're gonna win!
No, we're not.
TOM: And in a stunning
turn of events,
Chef Griffin
is eating his entire meal.
He'll have nothing to serve.
(buzzer sounds)
(panting)
Well, that's it.
If Chef Quagmire
has prepared a dish of any kind,
he wins this competition.
Let's see what he has.
A warm packet
of tartar sauce
brought in
from somewhere else.
"When are you gonna use that?"
Bonnie said.
We have a winner!
(crowd cheering)
Peter, you threw
the cook-off for me?
I couldn't take
your dream away...
Heart attack!
...from you, buddy.
You're the...
Mini stroke!
...one with the real...
Heart attack!
...talent. You...
...deserve the show...
Regular stroke!
...not me.
You're a good
friend, Peter.
But... I don't want
a show either.
You don't?
Of course not.
I mean, look what
the show did to us.
It destroyed the most
important friendship I have.
JOE:
Thanks.
You know what?
Let's end this for good.
How?
The same way Paula Deen
got her cooking show
taken off the air.
By saying the one word
you can't come back from.
What?
Say the word? Right now?
Yeah. Together.
Ready?
You bet.
(both inhale)
CLEVELAND: You could have
just quit the show.
Thank you for watching "Family Guy" on
www.FOX-fan.ru